Singer-actor Wang Yibo has returned for the second season of Exploring the Unknown with Wang Yibo,
歌手兼演员王一博回归《探索心境·王一博》第二季
in which he unveils a new identity — a rock climber.
在节目中，他展现了全新身份——攀岩爱好者
Produced by the Discovery Channel and co-presented by Tencent Video and Warner Bros., the outdoor reality show has been streaming on Tencent Video since Nov 28.
该户外真人秀由探索频道出品，腾讯视频与华纳兄弟联合呈现，自11月28日起在腾讯视频播出
Guided by Oscar-winning director Jimmy Chin
在奥斯卡获奖导演金国威的指导下
— also a professional mountain athlete — as his mentor,
金国威同时也是职业山地运动员，担任他的导师
Wang embarked on a climbing road trip across North America,
王一博开启了穿越北美的攀岩之旅
traveling more than 1,000 kilometers over six weeks.
六周内行程超过1000公里
Together, they explored a wide range of climbing styles, including sport climbing,
两人一同探索了多种攀岩方式，包括运动攀岩
traditional climbing, aid climbing, deep-water soloing, and big-wall climbing.
传统攀登、器械攀登、深水独攀以及大岩壁攀登
The show's first season, which followed Wang as he joined six explorers on expeditions to six physically extreme destinations,
节目第一季记录了王一博与六位探险家一同前往六个极限地点探险的过程
received a rating of 9.8 out of 10 on Tencent Video.
第一季在腾讯视频获得9.8分的高分评价
Capturing emotional moments of Wang and fellow explorers conquering fear and pushing their limits,
节目记录了王一博与探险家们克服恐惧、突破极限的感人瞬间
the first season won a Gold Telly at the 46th Annual Telly Awards
第一季荣获第46届泰利奖金奖
— often regarded as the documentary industry's equivalent of the Oscars.
该奖项被誉为纪录片行业的“奥斯卡”
According to the producers,
据制作方表示
Wang chose rock climbing for the new season because he enjoys the feeling of "ascending upward"
王一博选择攀岩作为新一季主题，是因为他享受“向上攀登”的感觉
after several rounds of discussion with the documentary's creative team.
在与纪录片创作团队多轮讨论后确定
To prepare for the season, Wang underwent systematic training and practiced outdoors with a coach, learning safety knowledge and rope techniques.
为了本季节目，王一博接受了系统训练，跟随教练户外练习，学习安全知识与绳索技术
He also proactively studied the differences among various climbing disciplines, such as distinctions in gear usage and protection methods between sport climbing and traditional climbing.
他还主动学习不同攀岩项目的区别，如运动攀岩与传统攀岩在装备使用和保护方式上的差异